ABDULLAHI TOHEEB

Software Developer

Lagos, Nigeria (+234) 704-561-9906 biodunbio14@gmail.com https://toheebb.netlify.app https://github.com/majorshuga

SKILLS

- Front-end: React, Redux-Toolkit, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Vue, Typescript

- Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, NestJs

- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL

- Version Control: Git

- Others: Laravel, Firebase, REST API, Heroku, Unix, Solidity, AWS,

ElectronJS, C programming, PHP, Selenium

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A committed and proactive software developer specializing in programming techniques to develop creative and innovative applications tailored to specific requirements. Demonstrates strong organizational and prioritization skills to achieve tight deadlines. A motivational and inspirational leader who excels in successful and productive team environments.

OBJECTIVE

Results-driven full stack developer with a passion for building innovative web applications. Leveraging 3 years of experience in front-end and back-end development, I am seeking a challenging position to utilize my technical expertise, collaborative mindset, and problem-solving skills to deliver high-quality software solutions. Committed to staying current with emerging technologies and industry trends, I aim to contribute to a dynamic team and drive the success of projects through efficient coding, seamless integration, and exceptional user experiences.

EXPERIENCE

UNITED STATES OF AFRICA, Volunteering - (Remote) Software engineer

February 2023 - To present

Responsibilities

- Collaborated with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Reviewed application requirements and interface designs.
- Developed and implemented highly responsive user interface components using React.
- Troubleshooting and debugging application codes.
- Monitored and improved front-end performance.
- Documented application changes and developed updates.

Elite Exclusive, Internship - (Remote) Fullstack engineer

May 2023 - To present

Responsibilities

- -Developed and implemented an advertisement bot, automating the advertising process and increasing efficiency.
- -Designed and programmed the Bot using Javascript and Nodejs library(Selenium) to target specific audiences and optimize ad placements across social media apps.
- =Conducted thorough testing and debugging to ensure the bot operated flawlessly,improving accuracy and reducing manual error.
- Regularly update the bot's features and functionality based on feedback, emerging trends and changing advertising platforms.
- Created regular content videos to increase user engagement.
- Organized and coordinated events with various organizations.
- Managed Elite student groups on campuses.

EVERYTHING FROZEN, Full Time - Fullstack engineer

Feb 2020 - March 2022

Responsibilities

- Analyzed user requirements and defined system functionality.
- Designed, developed, and updated the company website.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver projects.
- Debugged and fixed software defects.
- Maintained and improved existing software performance.
- Stayed up to date with emerging technologies and industry trends.

Hilite Technologies, Hybrid - Instructor html/css/javascript

Sept 2019 - Oct 2020

Responsibilities

- Assisted in curating learning resources for the course.
- Provided coaching and support to students.
- Monitored student engagement and provided feedback.
- Conducted code reviews and graded class exercises.
- Created relevant learning content and practice activities.

Kudi Crypto, Remote Nigeria - Fullstack engineer

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

Responsibilities

- Developed and maintained front-end web applications using React.
- Built and integrated back-end services using Node.js.
- Designed and implemented database structures, optimizing performance.
- Debugged and fixed issues across the entire stack.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver projects.
- Wrote and maintained technical documentation.

EDUCATION

University of Ilorin, Kwara, Nigeria - B.sc Mathematics

Dec 2015 - Sep 2019